<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflections</title>
    <link>http://ann.chiramattel.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 20:47:54 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://ann.chiramattel.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversation As Interface</title>
      <link>http://ann.chiramattel.com/post/conversation-as-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 20:47:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ann.chiramattel.com/post/conversation-as-interface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The User Interface is going beyond UI and voice recognition to the new trend of using conversation as a new way to engage with customers, i.e. &lt;strong&gt;Conversation As Interface&lt;/strong&gt;. It is a more natural form of communication, especially for question-answer / interview experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there is an emerging trend of companies opening their chat bot API to third party developers. Facebook &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2016/01/05/facebook-messenger-bots/&#34;&gt;has been doing experiments&lt;/a&gt; in their Messenger app allowing a few developers like Uber, Assist etc. to create chat bots. They are &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2016/04/07/facebook-chatbots/&#34;&gt;expected to announce&lt;/a&gt; opening up the SDK to all in next week’s F8 conference. Microsoft &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2016/03/30/microsoft-is-bringing-bots-to-skype-and-everywhere-else/&#34;&gt;released a Bot Framework&lt;/a&gt; in Build last week and this supports multiple channels – Slack, SMS, Skype etc. Similarly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2016/03/24/line-builds-out-its-chat-app-for-businesses-as-facebook-messenger-threat-looms-large/&#34;&gt;Line&lt;/a&gt; announced its SDK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chat bots could be a new way to reach customers even when the app is not installed. And if they support deep linking, then developers can deliver a smooth transition into sepcific flows in the app. This is a great opportunity to be where our users are. It will be interesting to see how this idea pans out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ann.chiramattel.com/img/bot-framework.png&#34; alt=&#34;Bot Framework&#34; title=&#34;Bots&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://ann.chiramattel.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 20:54:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ann.chiramattel.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software developer skilled in iOS, ReactNative, JavaScript, C#, .NET. Loves to learn and experiment. The latest contribution has been developing TurboTax iOS app from ground up last year. Always looking for multiple ways to improve the user experience as well as tech hygeine. I believe that building the product right is as important as building the right product.
I love coding @&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/annjose&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;, tweet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/annjose&#34;&gt;@annjose&lt;/a&gt;, and connect @LinkedIn&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post from Hugo</title>
      <link>http://ann.chiramattel.com/post/first-post-from-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:49:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ann.chiramattel.com/post/first-post-from-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first blog post created by &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a simple, fast and powerful blogging engine written in Go. Setting up my blog on Hugo was quick and easy; it took less than 4 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have set this up such that I publish the content to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt;, so the publish workflow is as simple as writing some Markdown and a git push. &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&#34;&gt;This is a good tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on how to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what I love about Hugo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static content generation, which means blazing fast rendering, no need to manage databases, VMs etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very easy to publish content - create content in markdown and simple git push&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No dependency issues; literally runs out of the box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highly customizable UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good opportunity to learn &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I am just loving Hugo. Next step is to explore it further and customize it to my heart&amp;rsquo;s content.
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://ann.chiramattel.com/img/hugo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hugo&#34; title=&#34;Hugo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>