<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career on Reflections</title>
    <link>https://annjose.com/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in career on Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2023. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 17:54:12 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://annjose.com/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week in Review - Week #2</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 17:54:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week2/</guid>
      <description>OK, here we are at Week #2 of the &amp;ldquo;new beginning&amp;rdquo; I set forth mid October - a journey which did not get a specific name, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. I guess some things are better served unnamed, yeah? Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s jump into the review. As always, this is free flow writing and I will follow the same format as last week&amp;rsquo;s review.
What I did during the week An honest review of this week should start by reviewing the goals I set out at the beginning of the week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week in Review - Week #1</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 19:14:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week1/</guid>
      <description>It has been a week since I started my leave of absence to pivot my career to be more hands on in tech. Here is how my Week 1 went. This is mostly a stream of consciousness instead of a well-formatted post, because it was important that I publish it at the end of the week - progress not perfection!
What I did during the week started learning two JavaScript courses in parallel - Modern JavaScript by Execute Program and Learn JavaScript by Jad Joubran.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new beginning</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/new-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 10:44:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/new-beginning/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, I stood at the crossroads of my career thinking about my next chapter. I loved my job, my team, and was at the peak of my career as a leader. Yet, I yearned for a return to the world of hands-on development, where I could immerse myself in the flow of code.
The more I thought about it, the more I was convinced that I want to pivot my career towards the goal of coding, learning and building with tech.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
