<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hugo on Reflections</title>
    <link>https://annjose.com/topics/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hugo on Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2023. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 14:09:57 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://annjose.com/topics/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading my blog engine Hugo and content</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/upgrade-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 14:09:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/upgrade-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Today I upgraded my blog engine Hugo from version 0.30.0 to 0.73.0. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I upgraded, so I was not sure how easy or difficult it will be. The upgrade completed quickly, but my entire home page (running locally) went blank right after the upgrade. With a good amount of googling, reading through the documentation and a few tweaks in my folder structure, I was able to bring it back up and running and published it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display mathematical expressions in blog</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/display-math-expressions-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 07:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/display-math-expressions-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>As part of my Machine Learning course, I learned a useful trick which I will share hoping that it may help someone or I myself can refer to it later. The problem at hand was how to display the mathematical expressions that calculate cost function, gradient descent etc. in a blog or web page. In OneNote, you can do it using OneNote Equation tool earlier, but I wanted to do the same in my blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post from Hugo</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/first-post-from-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:49:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/first-post-from-hugo/</guid>
      <description>This is my first blog post created by Hugo, a simple, fast and powerful blogging engine written in Go. Setting up my blog on Hugo was quick and easy; it took less than 4 hours.
I have set this up such that I publish the content to GitHub pages, so the publish workflow is as simple as writing some Markdown and a git push. This is a good tutorial on how to do this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
