<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Reflections</title>
    <link>https://annjose.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2025. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 13:13:12 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://annjose.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hands-On: Mobile AI with Gemma - iOS, Android</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/mobile-on-device-ai-hands-on-gemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 13:13:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/mobile-on-device-ai-hands-on-gemma/</guid>
      <description>In our previous post, Mobile On-device AI: Smarter and Faster Private Apps, we explored the fundamentals of running AI locally on mobile devices. Now, it&amp;rsquo;s time to get hands-on and see this technology in action!&#xA;This practical guide walks you through implementing mobile on-device AI using Google&amp;rsquo;s powerful Gemma model family, including the cutting-edge Gemma 3n. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn to deploy these models across iOS, Android, and web platforms using industry-standard frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile On-device AI: Smarter and Faster Private Apps</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/mobile-on-device-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 09:02:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/mobile-on-device-ai/</guid>
      <description>AI is reshaping how we live and work - thanks to significant advancements in model capabilities and computational power centered in cloud infrastructure. At the same time, the mobile devices we carry every day - our phones and tablets - are becoming increasingly powerful. As a developer who loves exploring AI and has built mobile apps, I am fascinated by the idea of these two worlds of mobile and AI converging.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edge AI Essentials</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/edge-ai-essentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 12:32:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/edge-ai-essentials/</guid>
      <description>Every day we&amp;rsquo;re seeing fantastic advancements in AI, thanks to more data and powerful computers. This may make it seem like the future of AI is all about getting even more data and bigger computers. But I believe a critical and rapidly evolving piece of the puzzle is about bringing the Intelligence of Artificial Intelligence onto the devices where the data originates (eg: our phones, cameras, and IoT devices) and doing the &amp;ldquo;smarts&amp;rdquo; using their own computing capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare AutoRAG: RAG on auto-pilot</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/cloudflare-autorag-step-by-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 17:54:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/cloudflare-autorag-step-by-step/</guid>
      <description>We know that RAG (Retrieval Augmented Generation) is a reliable mechanism to augment LLMs with up-to-date data and ground them on facts relevant to the context of the user query, thereby reducing hallucination. When set up properly, it works pretty well. Companies like Perplexity AI and enterprise applications use RAG extensively.&#xA;However, building a RAG pipeline on your own from scratch can be complex and high maintenance. You need to assemble your data sources, chunk the data, index it, generate embeddings, and store them in a vector database.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which browser cares about privacy the most?</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/browsers-privacy-compare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:14:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/browsers-privacy-compare/</guid>
      <description>I stopped using Chrome a long time ago due to privacy concerns, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been switching between Firefox, Edge, and occasionally Brave. But I never spent the time to fully compare these browsers and analyze which one best suits my needs. Today, I decided to look deeply into these browsers and ended up going down a rabbit hole of researching their privacy features.&#xA;Why is this important? Every time we browse a website, we are sharing bits of our digital life with companies we don&amp;rsquo;t know.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibe coding a Pomodoro app with AI</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/vibe-coding-pomodoro-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 15:18:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/vibe-coding-pomodoro-app/</guid>
      <description>Today I tried something fun - built a Pomodoro timer app mostly by talking to AI instead of typing code myself. And guess what - there is a term for it - vibe coding, coined by Andrej Karpathy 😎.&#xA;I have done it a few times before, but this is the first time I am using it to build a full app. I wanted to create something that was useful and worked well, so I chose the Pomodoro timer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining Strength: A Fitness Milestone</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/reimagine-fitness-milestone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:24:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/reimagine-fitness-milestone/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, if you had told me I’d be deadlifting 155 lbs, I would have laughed and said, &amp;ldquo;No way!&amp;rdquo; But here I am, doing it—something I never thought possible.&#xA;In a previous post in my reimagine journey, I talked about reframing milestones to focus on consistency rather than arbitrary goals. At the time, I was working out on my own, trying to stay active with strength training and Zone 2 walks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Claude Code: First Impressions</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/claude-code-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 04:32:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/claude-code-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>Today I tried Claude Code, the new agentic coding tool announced by Anthropic this morning. Unlike other agentic tools, Claude Code is a CLI tool.&#xA;Claude has been my favorite AI coding partner so far. I use it via GitHub Copilot and as standalone through its web interface. I was curious to see how it works in CLI and decided to give it a try.&#xA;In this post, I share my first impressions of using Claude Code - how I set it up, what I loved about it, what I didn&amp;rsquo;t, and how it compares to other similar tools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chrome Side Panel</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/chrome-side-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:15:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/chrome-side-panel/</guid>
      <description>Of late, I have been building and learning about browser extensions for a few projects. It was surprising to learn that there are many ways to build UI for these extensions and the most interesting one was the Side Panel UI available to Chrome extensions. In this post, I will talk about the Chrome side panel, how to build one and the advantages and limitations of using it.&#xA;The Chrome side panel It is a vertical panel that opens on either side of the browser window, providing quick access to your bookmarks, history, reading list, and Google Lens.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vercel v0.dev: A hands-on review</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/v0-dev-firsthand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 15:54:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/v0-dev-firsthand/</guid>
      <description>I have been using many Vercel products in my web projects - for example, their Next.js app framework, deployment infrastructure and Vercel AI SDK. I love these tools because are easy to use and onboard, they are reliable and fast - and most of them are open source, which is fantastic ❤️.&#xA;Their latest innovation is v0.dev, an AI-powered tool that helps you build frontend applications using a conversational chat interface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compare AI Tools: LLMs and AI Assistants</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/compare-ai-tools-llms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 17:22:33 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/compare-ai-tools-llms/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we will compare the most popular AI tools (frontier models and AI assistants) based on its capabilities, limitations and my personal experience of using them day-to-day.&#xA;In order to accomodate the multiple dimensions of each model, this comparison is represented as mind maps in three parts:&#xA;Language models - the most popular text-based models that are used for text-to-text content generation. AI assistants - the chatbots that are powered by one or more of the above models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Browser Extensions: Part 2 - Advanced Concepts</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/browser-extn-adv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:24:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/browser-extn-adv/</guid>
      <description>This is the second part of my blog series on browser extensions. Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into advanced concepts including TypeScript integration, service workers, and programmatic script injection. For a solid foundation, I recommend reading Browser Extensions: Part 1 - Introduction before tackling these more complex topics.&#xA;How to use TypeScript in browser extensions By default, browser extensions use JavaScript as the programming language in the content scripts. However, TypeScript is more type safe and reliable to write the business logic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Browser Extensions: Part 1 - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/browser-extn-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:12:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/browser-extn-intro/</guid>
      <description>Imagine a world where every website adapts to your specific needs in real-time, securely and easily, without selling your data to third party companies. It will be cool, right? Yes and it is possible - thanks to Browser extensions.&#xA;In this post, we will learn about browser extensions - what they are, why you should build them and how to build them. We will conclude by looking at a few issues that come up frequently while building an extension and how to troubleshoot them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reimagine Journey - A Big Milestone</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/reimagine-milestone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 12:49:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/reimagine-milestone/</guid>
      <description>Nine months ago, I started the Reimagine Journey to shift my career from engineering leadership to hands-on technology, specifically focusing on my health, personal growth and advanced tech skills. The long extended leave gave me the time and space to reflect on what I truly love and shape the next chapter of my career. It gave me the opportunity to determine how I want to live the rest of my life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perplexity AI: Insights from the CEO Aravind Srinivas</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/perplexity-ai-ceo-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 20:21:42 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/perplexity-ai-ceo-insights/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I watched an interview of Aravind Srinivas, the CEO of Perplexity AI (https://www.perplexity.ai). It is a three-hour interview done by Lex Fridman where Aravind talked about the major breakthroughs in AI that brought us to LLMs, the mission of Perplexity, how the technology works, his vision of the future of search and web in general, and some valuable advice for startup founders and young people.&#xA;Fascinating interview - highly recommended for everyone to watch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perplexity AI: A Deep Dive</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/perplexity-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 16:19:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/perplexity-ai/</guid>
      <description>Perplexity AI (https://www.perplexity.ai) has been gaining attention in the world of chatbots and large language models. I had heard about it in a few forums and mentioned by industry leaders like Jensen Huang and Kelsey Hightower. In fact, I had created an account and tried it out a few times earlier this year, but didn&amp;rsquo;t take it much seriously.&#xA;All that changed last week when I watched this recent interview of Perplexity CEO Aravind Srinivas by Lex Fridman.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Apple of AI</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/apple-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 20:14:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/apple-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>The standout feature unveiled at this week&amp;rsquo;s Apple WWDC 2024 event was Apple Intelligence, a personal intelligence system that will be integrated into multiple platforms - iOS 18, iPadOS 18 and macOS Sequoia.&#xA;What is Apple Intelligence? Apple Intelligence comprises of multiple highly-capable and efficient generative models - large language models and diffusion models. These models include on-device models as well as server-based foundation models.&#xA;The foundation models are trained on Apple&amp;rsquo;s open-source AXLearn library for deep learning, built on top of JAX (Python library for accelerated computing and transformation) and XLA (Accelerated Linear Algebra, an open-source ML compiler).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next.js - Migrate from Pages to App Router</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/nextjs-migrate-pages-app-router/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 12:42:25 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/nextjs-migrate-pages-app-router/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, Next.js introduced App Router, a new way to build React applications using the latest features like React Server components and streaming. This was included in Next.js version 13 and is meant to replace the Pages Router eventually. I have been using the App Router for all my builder projects for a while now. In fact, I usually kicked off projects with the standard create-next-app script that starts a new app from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPT-4 Turbo Vision: In Action</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/gpt-4-vision-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 21:12:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/gpt-4-vision-in-action/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a few months since OpenAI announced GPT-4 Turbo with Vision a model capable of understanding images and answering questions based on visual input. Recently, I decided to leverage this in a real app and got valuable insights. This post is a quick summary of my learnings from that experience.&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to use the model through ChatGPT and the Open AI API so that you can can integrate it into any application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to customize session data in NextAuth</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/how-to-customize-nextauth-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 10:25:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/how-to-customize-nextauth-session/</guid>
      <description>Of late, I have been diving into Next.js and absolutely loving it. I wanted to put my learnings to practice, so I started building an app to solve a personal pain point. Along the way, I wanted to add authentication for my app and decided to use NextAuth, the go-to auth library for Next.js. Overall, it was a great experience, with a few humps along the way, but in the end, it all worked out well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Run Code Llama 70B locally</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/run-code-llama-70B-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 16:42:25 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/run-code-llama-70B-locally/</guid>
      <description>Today, Meta AI announced they are releasing a new model Code Llama 70B, a higher performing LLM to generate code. This was exciting news and we have to try it out immediately.&#xA;In this post, I will do a walk-through of how to download and use the new model and how it compares to other code generating models like GPT-4.&#xA;As usual, the best way to run the inference on any model locally is to run Ollama.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Learning to Building</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/learning-to-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 20:13:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/learning-to-building/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last shared an update on my Reimagine journey that started three months ago. Initially, I used to share my progress every week and it helped me build momentum during the early stages. But after some time, this weekly ritual became tedious - sometimes taking up an entire day for a single post. So I decided to share updates based on significant milestones rather than tying them to specific points in time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye and Thank You 2023</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/goodbye-thankyou-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 12:28:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/goodbye-thankyou-2023/</guid>
      <description>Today is a beautiful day, just two more days to end the beautiful year of 2023 - a pivotal year of my career and life.&#xA;Reflecting back on the year, I am grateful and happy that I was able to experience the year in good health in the midst of wonderful people - my family, friends, and my team/colleagues at Intuit. Now is the perfect time to say goodbye to the year and share the invaluable lessons I have learned along the way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week in Review - Week #5</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 14:21:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week5/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Week #5 review of my remagine journey. The previous week&amp;rsquo;s reviews and the full series can be found at new-beginning tag collection.&#xA;What I was able to do this week First things first - I was able to get out of the rut from last week. if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what I am talking about, see last&amp;rsquo;s week review Week #4 Review where it was rough for me in terms of motivation and learning routine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week in Review - Week #4</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 09:11:33 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week4/</guid>
      <description>Yes, it is week #4 of my remagine journey and it&amp;rsquo;s time for the review. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t post it last week because of reasons I will explain below. The previous week&amp;rsquo;s reviews and the full series can be found at new-beginning tag collection.&#xA;What I was able to do this week Ok, here is the honest, bitter, truth - this week (week #4) was super rough for me - in terms of learning and reaching the goals I had set out at the beginning of the week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI DevDay 2023 - Observations &amp; Learnings</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/openai-devday-2023-observations-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 09:02:53 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/openai-devday-2023-observations-learnings/</guid>
      <description>This is the fast follow (Part 2) of the previous post OpenAI DevDay 2023 - Highlights (aka Part 1) where I shared the highlights and the announcements made at OpenAI DevDay 2023.&#xA;In this post right here, I will share my observations - about the event and OpenAI tech - and my learnings - from talking to people during the event and by trying out the tech hands-on. So, let&amp;rsquo;s jump in!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI DevDay 2023 - Highlights</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/openai-devday-2023-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:32:13 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/openai-devday-2023-highlights/</guid>
      <description>This week I attended the Open AI Dev Day on 6 Nov 2023 at SVN West, San Francisco. This event was special in many ways - for me, this is the first conference I attended since the pandemic and the first one during my new journey; for OpenAI, this is their first developer conference ever! So I think it deserves a dedicated blog post to share the highlights, key takeaways and my observations, right?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week in Review - Week #3</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 21:32:43 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week3/</guid>
      <description>This post has been sitting in my draft for two weeks, waiting for my time to polish and post. But then as usual, I never got to it and it just stayed there. Anyway, now I am gonna just publish. So if you see typos or mistakes, please lmk. Progress, not perfection, yeah?&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s time to review Week #3 of my reimagine journey. The previous week&amp;rsquo;s reviews and the full series be found at new-beginning tag collection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week in Review - Week #2</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 17:54:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week2/</guid>
      <description>OK, here we are at Week #2 of the &amp;ldquo;new beginning&amp;rdquo; I set forth mid October - a journey which did not get a specific name, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. I guess some things are better served unnamed, yeah? Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s jump into the review. As always, this is free flow writing and I will follow the same format as last week&amp;rsquo;s review.&#xA;What I did during the week An honest review of this week should start by reviewing the goals I set out at the beginning of the week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week in Review - Week #1</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 19:14:02 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week1/</guid>
      <description>It has been a week since I started my leave of absence to pivot my career to be more hands on in tech. Here is how my Week 1 went. This is mostly a stream of consciousness instead of a well-formatted post, because it was important that I publish it at the end of the week - progress not perfection!&#xA;What I did during the week started learning two JavaScript courses in parallel - Modern JavaScript by Execute Program and Learn JavaScript by Jad Joubran.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new beginning</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/new-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 10:44:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/new-beginning/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, I stood at the crossroads of my career thinking about my next chapter. I loved my job, my team, and was at the peak of my career as a leader. Yet, I yearned for a return to the world of hands-on development, where I could immerse myself in the flow of code.&#xA;The more I thought about it, the more I was convinced that I want to pivot my career towards the goal of coding, learning and building with tech.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPT-4 Technical Report Highlights</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/gpt-4-tech-report-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 12:59:18 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/gpt-4-tech-report-highlights/</guid>
      <description>OpenAI published the GPT-4 Technical Report on 27 Mar 2023. I wanted to read it immediately but was intimidated by the fact that it is a 100-page document. It turns out that it was not as difficult as I anticipated, it can be easily read over a weekend. The best part is that this report describes the key terminologies and methodologies used in the development of GPT-4. It&amp;rsquo;s always beneficial to obtain this information directly from the source.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog about ChatGPT in three different ways</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro-3-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 22:57:43 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro-3-ways/</guid>
      <description>Ever since ChatGPT was released to the public last November, I&amp;rsquo;ve been eager to write a blog about it. However, the daunting prospect of facing a blank screen kept me from starting the task, and I found myself procrastinating. Today, I finally summoned the courage to begin writing, but with a few tweaks from my usual approach.&#xA;Allow me to describe the meta experiment to understand how I can utilize ChatGPT to help me write the blog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT - An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 21:59:18 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few months, ChatGPT has captured my attention through numerous forums, articles and AI experts. I am fascinated by this technology and learning more about it everyday. With this introductory post, I hope to share my knowledge and insights on ChatGPT - how it works, its capabilities and limitations, potential pitfalls, and future prospects.&#xA;Note - Just for fun, I did an experiment to write two more versions of this post - one that was written by ChatGPT itself using a rough outline I provided, and another also written by ChatGPT, but imrprovised from my original post.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT Introduction - written by ChatGPT using Ann&#39;s outline</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro-written-by-chatgpt-from-my-outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 20:54:11 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro-written-by-chatgpt-from-my-outline/</guid>
      <description>Note - This post is written by ChatGPT expanding on the outline of my original post An Introduction to ChatGPT - section by section. This is a fun exercise to demonstrate the potential of ChatGPT and how it can change how we create content, art and code. You can see the full results of the experiment at Blog about ChatGPT in three different ways.&#xA;Have you ever heard of ChatGPT? It&amp;rsquo;s a large language model that has taken the AI world by storm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT Introduction - rewritten by ChatGPT from Ann&#39;s originial post</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro-rewritten-by-chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 18:25:12 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro-rewritten-by-chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>Note - This post is written by ChatGPT by rewriting my original post An Introduction to ChatGPT - section by section. This is a fun exercise to demonstrate the potential of ChatGPT and how it can change how we create content, art and code. You can see the full results of the experiment at Blog about ChatGPT in three different ways.&#xA;As an avid learner and technology enthusiast, I have been following the advancements and discussions surrounding ChatGPT in various forums and sources.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grit: Passion &amp; Perseverance</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/grit-passion-perseverance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 20:55:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/grit-passion-perseverance/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I started watching the YouTube series Talks at Google and today I came across this video Grit: The Power of Passion and Perseverance by Angela Duckworth, the researcher, author and professor of Psychology at UPenn. I had seen her TED talk earlier and this talk was even better where whe unpacked a lot of details on the concept of grit. This post is to share the key takeaways I got from the talk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading my blog engine Hugo and content</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/upgrade-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 14:09:57 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/upgrade-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Today I upgraded my blog engine Hugo from version 0.30.0 to 0.73.0. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I upgraded, so I was not sure how easy or difficult it will be. The upgrade completed quickly, but my entire home page (running locally) went blank right after the upgrade. With a good amount of googling, reading through the documentation and a few tweaks in my folder structure, I was able to bring it back up and running and published it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tinkering with VS Code, MacOS and C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/vscode-macos-cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 22:32:55 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/vscode-macos-cpp/</guid>
      <description>After a long time, I got the time to tinker with something fun and learn from it, thanks to the week-long break from work. The task at hand is to set up Visual Studio for Mac to compile/run/debug C++ programs. Why, you may wonder - for the past few months, I have been craving to learn something different and I was hooked when I saw the book Data Structures and Algorithms in C++ by Adam Drozdek.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What do I really want</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/what-do-i-really-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 11:26:39 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/what-do-i-really-want/</guid>
      <description>The other day I watched a TED video where the presenter urged the audience to ask the question What do you really want? That got me thinking what do I really want. It is an interesting question to ask myself, since I have tried different roles and responsibilites - broad and deep - in the last couple of years.&#xA;So I was pleasantly surprised when I found the book Data Structures and Algorithms in C++ by Adam Drozdek on my bookshelf.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to mock network requests in iOS</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/mocking-network-requests-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 20:00:52 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/mocking-network-requests-ios/</guid>
      <description>One of the challenges of mobile application development is to ensure that the application is resilient to various error responses from the services that are consumed by the application. Mobile devices are more susceptible to network connectivity issues, timeout etc. So we need to take extra care to make sure that we test all error scenarios and handle them in a meaningful manner.&#xA;What and Why of Mocking Even though we are convinced about the benefits of testing server errors, these services are running in Production serving real customer requests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn GraphQL By Example</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/graphql-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 14:30:28 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/graphql-intro/</guid>
      <description>I have been using GraphQL in my work project for a few months now and I love it. But all my learnings of this technology have been in a hurry and mainly from a consumption standpoint as a mobile developer. So I wanted to learn it much deeper, tinker with it and finally write this blog to share my learnings and cement my understanding. Finally got the time to do it this weekend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift 4.2 - What&#39;s New</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/swift42-whats-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 20:09:12 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/swift42-whats-new/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I would like to share what&amp;rsquo;s new in Swift 4.2. All the code displayed in this post is available at my GitHub repo my-learnings/Swift4.2.&#xA;Random Number Generation Swift 4.2 added random number generator API to standard library. You can use it on Int, Double, Float, CGFloat and Bool. It also provides a convenient API randomElement which returns a random element from a sequence It also provides the APIs shuffle and shuffled to shuffle a sequence 1 2 let randomInt = Int.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GraceHopper 2018 Highlights</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/ghc-2018-hightlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 21:17:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/ghc-2018-hightlights/</guid>
      <description>I am at the Houston IAH airport waiting to board the flight to go home after 3 days of inspiration, motivation, technology, friendship and pure awesomeness. Yes, I was at Grace Hopper Celebration 2018 (aka GHC 2018), the world&amp;rsquo;s biggest gathering of women technologists. This year, GHC has 20,000 attendees representing 90 countries. It was such an inspiring experience for me that I thought I should share my experiences and learnings with you my friends.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fastlane</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/fastlane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 12:02:23 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/fastlane/</guid>
      <description>Fastlane is a suite of simple yet powerful tools to automate building and releasing iOS and Android apps. It takes care of the mundane tasks of mobile application development like generating screenshots, managing provisioning profiles, code signing, beta deployments and releasing the application. It is very popular in the mobile developer community and the best part - it is completely open source.&#xA;The Toolchain fastlane comes out-of-the-box with a set of very good tools (better known as actions) such as:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google IO 2017</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/GoogleIO-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 03:37:57 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/GoogleIO-2017/</guid>
      <description>I had the wonderful opportunity to attend Google I/O last week and absolutely loved it. I learned a lot of things during the three days. Btw, it was tiring too with the continuous sessions and the sunny Sun.&#xA;This post is an attempt to share the main highlights and the announcements that I found interesting. If you attended the event or watched the sessions online, let me know if there were more things that you found interesting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TDD in Xcode Playground</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/xcode-playgrounds-tdd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 02:02:31 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/xcode-playgrounds-tdd/</guid>
      <description>I use Xcode playground a lot in order to write code snippets - either to try out something that I read in a blog, or to demonstrate a code improvement that I want to suggest in a code review, or sometimes even to prototype a design before doing the full-blown implementation in Xcode project. During this experimentation phase, the correctness of the code was verified by analyzing the ouput displayed on the right-hand side column of the playground.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realm Mobile Platform</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/realm-announces-mobile-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 08:22:02 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/realm-announces-mobile-platform/</guid>
      <description>Realm is a company that I respect a lot because of their support for mobile developers and the open nature nature of their offerings. Their easy-to-use, blazingly fast Mobile database software supports all mobile platforms - iOS, Android, React Native and Xamarin, in Java, ObjC, Swift and C#. That is why I am happy to see that today they announced Realm Mobile Platform that combines Realm client side database with server-side technology (Object Server as they call it).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Display mathematical expressions in blog</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/display-math-expressions-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 07:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/display-math-expressions-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>As part of my Machine Learning course, I learned a useful trick which I will share hoping that it may help someone or I myself can refer to it later. The problem at hand was how to display the mathematical expressions that calculate cost function, gradient descent etc. in a blog or web page. In OneNote, you can do it using OneNote Equation tool earlier, but I wanted to do the same in my blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning - A new journey</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/machine-learning-coursera/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 20:05:54 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/machine-learning-coursera/</guid>
      <description>Few weeks ago, I started the Machine Learning course on Coursera by Andrew Ng of Stanford University. The course is great, learning a lot of new concepts. Sometimes it is hard, but it is really fun learning this new topic and brushing up the old Math lessons of Linear Algebra, matrix manipulation and derivatives.&#xA;The course starts with the basics, including a primer on Linear Algebra (it is optional, but I took it anyway since it has been more than a decade when I learned it in college).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReactNative in Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/react-native-visual-studio-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 21:22:02 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/react-native-visual-studio-code/</guid>
      <description>I have been thoroughly enjoying working on ReactNative projects, but was disappointed by the lack of a good debugging environment. I had tried multiple solutions like Nuclide (which I found it to be very slow), WebStorm with JSX plugins (which is mainly syntax recognition). So I had to always launch the app from Xcode/Android Studio, then attach Chrome Dev tools and keep switching between all three for debugging. This was frustrating, but there is hope&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conversation as Interface</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/conversation-as-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 20:47:54 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/conversation-as-interface/</guid>
      <description>The User Interface is going beyond UI and voice recognition to the new trend of using conversation as a new way to engage with customers, i.e. Conversation As Interface. It is a more natural form of communication, especially for question-answer / interview experiences.&#xA;Now there is an emerging trend of companies opening their chat bot API to third party developers. Facebook has been running many experiments in their Messenger app allowing a few developers like Uber, Assist etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First post from Hugo</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/first-post-from-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:49:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/first-post-from-hugo/</guid>
      <description>This is my first blog post created by Hugo, a simple, fast and powerful blogging engine written in Go. Setting up my blog on Hugo was quick and easy; it took less than 4 hours.&#xA;I have set this up such that I publish the content to GitHub pages, so the publish workflow is as simple as writing some Markdown and a git push. This is a good tutorial on how to do this.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
