<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>building on Reflections</title>
    <link>https://annjose.com/tags/building/</link>
    <description>Recent content in building on Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2024. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:15:21 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://annjose.com/tags/building/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chrome Side Panel</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/chrome-side-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:15:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/chrome-side-panel/</guid>
      <description>Of late, I have been building and learning about browser extensions for a few projects. It was surprising to learn that there are many ways to build UI for these extensions and the most interesting one was the Side Panel UI available to Chrome extensions. In this post, I will talk about the Chrome side panel, how to build one and the advantages and limitations of using it.&#xA;The Chrome side panel It is a vertical panel that opens on either side of the browser window, providing quick access to your bookmarks, history, reading list, and Google Lens.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Browser Extensions: Part 2 - Advanced Concepts</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/browser-extn-adv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:24:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/browser-extn-adv/</guid>
      <description>This is the second part of my blog series on browser extensions. Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into advanced concepts including TypeScript integration, service workers, and programmatic script injection. For a solid foundation, I recommend reading Browser Extensions: Part 1 - Introduction before tackling these more complex topics.&#xA;How to use TypeScript in browser extensions By default, browser extensions use JavaScript as the programming language in the content scripts. However, TypeScript is more type safe and reliable to write the business logic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Browser Extensions: Part 1 - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/browser-extn-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:12:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/browser-extn-intro/</guid>
      <description>Imagine a world where every website adapts to your specific needs in real-time, securely and easily, without selling your data to third party companies. It will be cool, right? Yes and it is possible - thanks to Browser extensions.&#xA;In this post, we will learn about browser extensions - what they are, why you should build them and how to build them. We will conclude by looking at a few issues that come up frequently while building an extension and how to troubleshoot them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to customize session data in NextAuth</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/how-to-customize-nextauth-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 10:25:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/how-to-customize-nextauth-session/</guid>
      <description>Of late, I have been diving into Next.js and absolutely loving it. I wanted to put my learnings to practice, so I started building an app to solve a personal pain point. Along the way, I wanted to add authentication for my app and decided to use NextAuth, the go-to auth library for Next.js. Overall, it was a great experience, with a few humps along the way, but in the end, it all worked out well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Learning to Building</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/learning-to-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 20:13:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/learning-to-building/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last shared an update on my Reimagine journey that started three months ago. Initially, I used to share my progress every week and it helped me build momentum during the early stages. But after some time, this weekly ritual became tedious - sometimes taking up an entire day for a single post. So I decided to share updates based on significant milestones rather than tying them to specific points in time.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
