<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>building on Reflections</title>
    <link>https://annjose.com/tags/building/</link>
    <description>Recent content in building on Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2024. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:12:32 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://annjose.com/tags/building/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Browser Extensions: What, Why and How</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/browser-extn-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:12:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/browser-extn-intro/</guid>
      <description>Imagine a world where every website adapts to your specific needs in real-time, securely and easily, without selling your data to third party companies. It will be cool, right? Yes and it is possible - thanks to Browser extensions.&#xA;In this post, we will learn about browser extensions - what they are, why you should build them and how to build them. We will conclude by looking at a few issues that come up frequently while building an extension and how to troubleshoot them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to customize session data in NextAuth</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/how-to-customize-nextauth-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 10:25:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/how-to-customize-nextauth-session/</guid>
      <description>Of late, I have been diving into Next.js and absolutely loving it. I wanted to put my learnings to practice, so I started building an app to solve a personal pain point. Along the way, I wanted to add authentication for my app and decided to use NextAuth, the go-to auth library for Next.js. Overall, it was a great experience, with a few humps along the way, but in the end, it all worked out well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Learning to Building</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/learning-to-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 20:13:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/learning-to-building/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last shared an update on my Reimagine journey that started three months ago. Initially, I used to share my progress every week and it helped me build momentum during the early stages. But after some time, this weekly ritual became tedious - sometimes taking up an entire day for a single post. So I decided to share updates based on significant milestones rather than tying them to specific points in time.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
