<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine-learning on Reflections</title>
    <link>https://annjose.com/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine-learning on Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2024. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 22:57:43 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://annjose.com/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blog about ChatGPT in three different ways</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro-3-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 22:57:43 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro-3-ways/</guid>
      <description>Ever since ChatGPT was released to the public last November, I&amp;rsquo;ve been eager to write a blog about it. However, the daunting prospect of facing a blank screen kept me from starting the task, and I found myself procrastinating. Today, I finally summoned the courage to begin writing, but with a few tweaks from my usual approach.&#xA;Allow me to describe the meta experiment to understand how I can utilize ChatGPT to help me write the blog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT - An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 21:59:18 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few months, ChatGPT has captured my attention through numerous forums, articles and AI experts. I am fascinated by this technology and learning more about it everyday. With this introductory post, I hope to share my knowledge and insights on ChatGPT - how it works, its capabilities and limitations, potential pitfalls, and future prospects.&#xA;Note - Just for fun, I did an experiment to write two more versions of this post - one that was written by ChatGPT itself using a rough outline I provided, and another also written by ChatGPT, but imrprovised from my original post.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT Introduction - rewritten by ChatGPT from Ann&#39;s originial post</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro-rewritten-by-chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 18:25:12 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/chatgpt-intro-rewritten-by-chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>Note - This post is written by ChatGPT by rewriting my original post An Introduction to ChatGPT - section by section. This is a fun exercise to demonstrate the potential of ChatGPT and how it can change how we create content, art and code. You can see the full results of the experiment at Blog about ChatGPT in three different ways.&#xA;As an avid learner and technology enthusiast, I have been following the advancements and discussions surrounding ChatGPT in various forums and sources.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
