<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal-Growth on Reflections</title>
    <link>https://annjose.com/tags/personal-growth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal-Growth on Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2025. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:24:23 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://annjose.com/tags/personal-growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining Strength: A Fitness Milestone</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/reimagine-fitness-milestone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 14:24:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/reimagine-fitness-milestone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, if you had told me I’d be deadlifting 155 lbs, I would have laughed and said, &amp;ldquo;No way!&amp;rdquo; But here I am, doing it—something I never thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/post/reimagine-milestone/&#34;&gt;post in my reimagine journey&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about reframing milestones to focus on consistency rather than arbitrary goals. At the time, I was working out on my own, trying to stay active with strength training and Zone 2 walks. I was making some progress, but it was small and I felt stuck. Looking back, I realize it wasn’t a lack of effort—it was a lack of structure, consistency, and progression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reimagine Journey - A Big Milestone</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/reimagine-milestone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 12:49:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/reimagine-milestone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nine months ago, I started the &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/post/new-beginning/&#34;&gt;Reimagine Journey&lt;/a&gt; to shift my career from engineering leadership to hands-on technology, specifically focusing on my health, personal growth and advanced tech skills. The long extended leave gave me the time and space to reflect on what I truly love and shape the next chapter of my career. It gave me the opportunity to determine how I want to live the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Learning to Building</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/learning-to-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 20:13:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/learning-to-building/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last shared an update on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/tags/new-beginning/&#34;&gt;Reimagine journey&lt;/a&gt; that started three months ago. Initially, I used to share my progress every week and it helped me build momentum during the early stages. But after some time, this weekly ritual became tedious - sometimes taking up an entire day for a single post. So I decided to share updates based on significant &lt;strong&gt;milestones&lt;/strong&gt; rather than tying them to specific &lt;strong&gt;points in time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye and Thank You 2023</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/goodbye-thankyou-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 12:28:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/goodbye-thankyou-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is a beautiful day, just two more days to end the beautiful year of 2023 - a pivotal year of my career and life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reflecting back on the year, I am grateful and happy that I was able to experience the year in good health in the midst of wonderful people - my family, friends, and my team/colleagues at Intuit. Now is the perfect time to say goodbye to the year and share the invaluable lessons I have learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week in Review - Week #5</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 14:21:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Week #5 review of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/post/new-beginning/&#34;&gt;remagine journey&lt;/a&gt;. The previous week&amp;rsquo;s reviews and the full series can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/tags/new-beginning/&#34;&gt;new-beginning tag collection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-was-able-to-do-this-week&#34;&gt;What I was able to do this week&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First things first - I was able to get out of the rut from last week. if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what I am talking about, see last&amp;rsquo;s week review &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week4/&#34;&gt;Week #4 Review&lt;/a&gt; where it was rough for me in terms of motivation and learning routine. But this week was different. Phew! ❣️&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week in Review - Week #4</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 09:11:33 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, it is week #4 of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/post/new-beginning/&#34;&gt;remagine journey&lt;/a&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;s time for the review. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t post it last week because of reasons I will explain below. The previous week&amp;rsquo;s reviews and the full series can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/tags/new-beginning/&#34;&gt;new-beginning tag collection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-was-able-to-do-this-week&#34;&gt;What I was able to do this week&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ok, here is the honest, bitter, truth - this week (week #4) was super rough for me - in terms of learning and reaching the goals I had set out at the beginning of the week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week in Review - Week #3</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 21:32:43 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post has been sitting in my draft for two weeks, waiting for my time to polish and post. But then as usual, I never got to it and it just stayed there. Anyway, now I am gonna just publish. So if you see typos or mistakes, please lmk. Progress, not perfection, yeah?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to review Week #3 of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/post/new-beginning/&#34;&gt;reimagine journey&lt;/a&gt;. The previous week&amp;rsquo;s reviews and the full series be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/tags/new-beginning/&#34;&gt;new-beginning tag collection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week in Review - Week #2</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 17:54:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OK, here we are at Week #2 of the &amp;ldquo;new beginning&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/post/new-beginning/&#34;&gt;I set forth mid October&lt;/a&gt; - a journey which did not get a specific name, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. I guess some things are better served unnamed, yeah? Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s jump into the review. As always, this is free flow writing and I will follow the same format as &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week1/&#34; title=&#34;Week In Review - Week 1&#34;&gt;last week&amp;rsquo;s review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-did-during-the-week&#34;&gt;What I did during the week&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An honest review of this week should start by reviewing the goals I set out at the beginning of the week. These are the goals I decided in &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week1/&#34; title=&#34;Week In Review - Week 1&#34;&gt;my last week&amp;rsquo;s review&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week in Review - Week #1</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 19:14:02 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/week-in-review-week1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a week since I started my leave of absence to pivot my career to be more hands on in tech. Here is how my Week 1 went. This is mostly a stream of consciousness instead of a well-formatted post, because it was important that I publish it at the end of the week - progress not perfection!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-did-during-the-week&#34;&gt;What I did during the week&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;started learning two JavaScript courses in parallel - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.executeprogram.com/courses/modern-javascript&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Modern JavaScript by Execute Program&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://learnjavascript.online/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Learn JavaScript by Jad Joubran&lt;/a&gt;. Each of these courses have different strengths - one is a typical structured course with a set of chapters each explaining a concept, a lot of examples and exercises, whereas the other one is a set of best practices of writing modern JavaScript. I think it is important to understand both. Also, the Execute Program course follows the spaced repetition format and hence limits the amount of material you can cover everyday.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new beginning</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/new-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 10:44:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/new-beginning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few months ago&lt;/strong&gt;, I stood at the crossroads of my career thinking about my next chapter. I loved my job, my team, and was at the peak of my career as a leader. Yet, I yearned for a return to the world of hands-on development, where I could immerse myself in the flow of code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The more I thought about it, the more I was convinced that I want to pivot my career towards the goal of coding, learning and building with tech. But I resisted the urge to act on impulse. Instead, I started a deliberate, step-by-step plan to execute this transition. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I approached it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
