<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web-development on Reflections</title>
    <link>https://annjose.com/tags/web-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web-development on Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2024. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 15:54:13 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://annjose.com/tags/web-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vercel v0.dev: My Firsthand Experience</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/v0-dev-firsthand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 15:54:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/v0-dev-firsthand/</guid>
      <description>I have been using many Vercel products in my web projects - for example, their Next.js app framework, deployment infrastructure and Vercel AI SDK. I love these tools because are easy to use and onboard, they are reliable and fast - and most of them are open source, which is fantastic ❤️.&#xA;Their latest innovation is v0.dev, an AI-powered tool that helps you build frontend applications using a conversational chat interface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Browser Extensions: What, Why and How</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/browser-extn-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:12:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/browser-extn-intro/</guid>
      <description>Imagine a world where every website adapts to your specific needs in real-time, securely and easily, without selling your data to third party companies. It will be cool, right? Yes and it is possible - thanks to Browser extensions.&#xA;In this post, we will learn about browser extensions - what they are, why you should build them and how to build them. We will conclude by looking at a few issues that come up frequently while building an extension and how to troubleshoot them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next.js - Migrate from Pages to App Router</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/nextjs-migrate-pages-app-router/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 12:42:25 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/nextjs-migrate-pages-app-router/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, Next.js introduced App Router, a new way to build React applications using the latest features like React Server components and streaming. This was included in Next.js version 13 and is meant to replace the Pages Router eventually. I have been using the App Router for all my builder projects for a while now. In fact, I usually kicked off projects with the standard create-next-app script that starts a new app from scratch.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
