<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coding-Assistants on Reflections</title>
    <link>https://annjose.com/tags/coding-assistants/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coding-Assistants on Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2025. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:23:08 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://annjose.com/tags/coding-assistants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Coding In Practice</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/agent-coding-in-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:23:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/agent-coding-in-practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://annjose.com/post/agentic-coding-basics/&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, I explained the basic concepts of agentic coding - the terminology, the constructs, when to use what. It was mostly theoretical. This post is the practical follow-up that describes how I actually build features with AI agents day to day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hesitate to call these &amp;lsquo;best practices&amp;rsquo; because in this fast moving space, it just means &amp;lsquo;what someone discovered last week&amp;rsquo;. So, think of this as a field report: here&amp;rsquo;s what works for me today, and why.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Coding: The Basic Concepts</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/agentic-coding-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:11:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/agentic-coding-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to think that I love coding, but in the last year, I came to realize that what I love more is &lt;em&gt;building&lt;/em&gt; - creating something useful and beautiful. Last year this time, my coding workflow was to fire up VS Code with  Claude in the browser or GitHub Copilot in &amp;lsquo;Ask&amp;rsquo; mode and brainstorm with a model, review solutions suggested by the LLM, copy code into the editor, test and deploy🚀. This was fun in the beginning, but soon the context-switching became tedious and broke the flow of building.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibe coding a Pomodoro app with AI</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/vibe-coding-pomodoro-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 15:18:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/vibe-coding-pomodoro-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I tried something fun - built a Pomodoro timer app mostly by talking to AI instead of typing code myself. And guess what - there is a term for it - &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vibe_coding&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;vibe coding&lt;/a&gt;, coined by Andrej Karpathy 😎.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have done it a few times before, but this is the first time I am using it to build a full app. I wanted to create something that was useful and worked well, so I chose the Pomodoro timer. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it went and my key takeaways from this way of building products.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Claude Code: First Impressions</title>
      <link>https://annjose.com/post/claude-code-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 04:32:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://annjose.com/post/claude-code-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I tried &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/agents-and-tools/claude-code&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Claude Code&lt;/a&gt;, the new agentic coding tool &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anthropic.com/news/claude-3-7-sonnet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;announced by Anthropic&lt;/a&gt; this morning. Unlike other agentic tools, Claude Code is a CLI tool.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Claude has been my favorite AI coding partner so far. I use it via GitHub Copilot and as standalone through its web interface. I was curious to see how it works in CLI and decided to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I share my first impressions of using Claude Code - how I set it up, what I loved about it, what I didn&amp;rsquo;t, and how it compares to other similar tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
